Stanley Ndagi

Software Engineer well versed with working in the Scrum - Agile methodology Worked across industries like fintech, agriculture, ecommerce, and education Experienced in remote work within cross-cultural, multinational teams with the collective goal of delivering value, gaining revenue, process optimization and/or reducing costs.

ndagis@gmail.com <u>GitHub</u>: NdagiStanley <u>LinkedIn</u>: ndagistanley

Fluency: English, Swahili

EXPERIENCE

Independent consultant (Remote Software Engineer)

NOV 2019 - PRESENT

These past months have seen me taking up projects where I collaborate with individuals and teams alike as a consultant. I am involved in software development, team structuring, project management, and talent sourcing.

My schedule creates more time for mentoring and training, and learning.

Andela, Nairobi Kenya

NOV 2015 - NOV 2019

Within this period, besides being a remote engineer in various teams, I wore several hats as summarised below.

Senior Software Engineer

JAN 2018 - NOV 2019

For 3 months, in the capacity of a **Product Manager**, I led a team of engineers in building an internal tool that would be used in fostering camaraderie among employees. This involved hiring team leads and developers, scoping work for different iterations of the MVP and leading stakeholder meetings with different departments and the Product Owner.

Software Engineer

NOV 2015 - JAN 2018

In the capacity of a **Technical Team Lead**, I led a team extending an open-source product. I led scoping, sprint planning and retros as well as did code reviews. All this, while mentoring these junior developers.

Bellwethr, Kansas City, Missouri, US Software Engineer | Platform and Machine Learning (Remote)

MAY 2019 - NOV 2019

Due to my **FullStack** experience, I worked on a greenfield project that involved ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) process from SOAP and REST API (Application Programming Interface)s and Data dumps, through AWS into a Data Lake supporting the main offerings of the business

I did a good deal of DevOps (Developer Operations), added best practices of CI/CD (Continuous Integration and Continuous Delivery or Deployment), improved local development and shipping incorporating Docker and Code Deploy on AWS

Collaborated on Database Design and System factoring in our Machine Learning models.

SKILLS

Programming:

<u>Python</u> (Tool of choice): Django, Flask, Scrapy, Pytorch, Jupyter, Apache Airflow <u>JavaScript</u>: VueJS, ReactJS, NodeJS

DBs: PostgresQL, MongoDB

Web: CSS3, HTML5, PWA, Polymer JS

Others: PHP

Tools:

<u>DevOps</u>: Docker, Chef, K8s

<u>CI/CD</u> (Continuous Integration and
Continuous Delivery or
Deployment):
CircleCI, SemaphoreCI

Cloud: GCP, AWS, Firebase, Netlify,

Vercel, Azure

Competencies:

Core:

BackEnd Development APIs: REST, GraphQL, SOAP DevOps

FrontEnd Development
Project & Product Management
Engineering Management
Technical Team Leadership
Data Engineering
Machine Learning & Artificial
Intelligence
IoT (Internet of Things)
Remote Work
Open Source
Version Control

WRITING

Technical Copywriting

Last updated: April 2021

Link to the most recent: https://stanmd.tk/cv

EXPERIENCE (Continued)

FarmLogs, Ann Arbor, Michigan, US Software Engineer (Remote)

AUG 2018 - JAN 2019

Extended FarmLogs GraphQL API among two other Backend engineers

Built internal ETL tools supporting user management and syncing data from several crop-trading external APIs

Launched a new product AutoHedge that involved decoupling and extending some functionality across the API to serve the current product and the new one that could be used separately or as an additional feature.

BrightHive, Greater Chicago Area, Illinois, US Software Engineer (Remote)

MAY 2017 - JULY 2018

As part of the initial development team, I was involved in System Design for the just-formed startup. Recommended tools, platforms and created team processes of development, documentation, code review and performance measurement.

Extended Open Source projects to fit our scope. Created APIs and CI/CD pipelines for proof-of-concept products that incorporated data-dumping and reporting functionalities via API across learning institutions and state departments of Education.

Enigma, New York — Data Engineer (Remote)

OCT 2016 - FEB 2017

Wrote ETL configuration files in a DSL that instructed how open data and customer data stored in a myriad of formats would be ingested.

EDUCATION

Udacity — AI programming with Python Nanodegree

JKUAT, Kenya — BSc. Information Technology

PROJECTS

VueDjango — *VueJS-Django-Webpack boilerplate* <u>https://qithub.com/NdaqiStanley/vue-django</u>

This boilerplate helps developers spin up a Django application that has VueJS baked in. <u>The project has been quoted in several technical articles</u>, <u>even in different languages</u>.

WRITING (Continued)

Technical Writer/ Editor

- CircleCI Guest Writers Program
- ScotchIO
- Packt Publishing Company

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

F8 hackathon finalist, 2019 My team was listed among the top 8 finalists

Andela Employee of the Year, 2016 Awardees epitomise the company's values:

Excellence, Passion, Integrity and Collaboration

VOLUNTEERING/ COMMUNITY

Team Lead, Volunteer Devs Open Digerati, Global

Hackathon Organising Lead, 2018 FishHackathon, Kenya edition

Speaker

ForLoop Abuja, Nigeria

Visionary

TechKln techkln.org

Mentor

- Bridging The Gap(An initiative by my Alumni)2019-Present
- Youth and Success Association (Kenyan non-profit) 2019
- Frauenloop

(German non-profit) 2017-2018

- KamiLimu

(Kenyan non-profit) 2017

Coach

DjangoGirls Nairobi, 2016

Last updated: April 2021

Link to the most recent: https://stanmd.tk/cv